NINGSUHEN WAIKHOM

Location: Noida, UP, India

Phone: +91-9899386296

Email: ningsuhen@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 25th Jan 1988

Languages: English, Hindi and Manipuri

Portfolio: ningsuhen.github.io

LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/ningsuhen</u>

Github: <u>github.com/ningsuhen</u>

Skype: <u>skype:ningsuhen</u>

Skype: <u>skype:ningsuhen</u>

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Generalist & avid practitioner of up-to-date software engineering methodologies like Agile (Continuous Integration & Delivery), TDD, BDD. Expertise in rapid web development, performance engineering & Devops. Broad understanding of UX Design, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Cloud Computing & Entrepreneurship. Contributor of LoopbackJS framework and other open source projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

✓ Indie Developer & Freelancer // Oct 2014 - Present

- Developed Backend and Front-end(Admin dashboard) of <u>JustMove App</u> using NodeJS, MongoDB, RabbitMQ & Google Fitness API.
- Developed Continuous Integration & Deployment System for JustMove App using Codeship, Elastic Beanstalk.
- Monitored New Relic and fixed critical performance Bugs in Open Source project StrongLoop <u>Loopback</u>.
- Developed an iOS Application called <u>NewPhonebook</u> with advanced Search, Contacts Cleanup and backup tools (iCloud, Google Drive & Dropbox support).

✓ Co-Founder @ Treepie Technologies Pvt. Ltd. // May 2014 - Sept 2014

- Developed Full-Stack Web application & iOS app of <u>lukup.me</u> which integrates with Facebook, Google Plus, LinkedIn, Twitter.
- Analyzed various APIs Facebook Graph, Google Plus, Twitter, LinkedIn and came up with a REST API specification which incorporates the best conventions.
- Developed Continuous Integration & Delivery System & Monitoring System. Enforced Behavior Driven Development for Server Side and Web Applications.

✓ Software Engineer -> Lead Software Engineer @ Adobe Systems India Pvt. Ltd. // Jan 2011 - April 2014

- Developed several prototypes of Video Streaming Solutions for clients using Day CQ & Adobe Media Server.
- Developed a Continuous Integration & Deployment Pipeline which allows rapid deployment into AWS infrastructure along with UI (Selenium) and Integration testing.
- Developed a Performance Console (Web Interface) which can spawn and run performance tests from 100s of AWS instances as clients. The tool is still in use in Adobe for performance testing.
- Initiated BDD(Behavior Driven Development) in the Team.
- Developed a Web Application for Internal Table Tennis Tournament with gamification using Django & BackboneJS.

✓ Subject Matter Expert @ Amdocs Development Centre India // May 2009 - Dec 2010

- Fixed several critical and obscure bugs of CRAMER and ASMS products.
- Developed Tools for automating various repetitive tasks in the Team using Java JMS & VBScript.
- Developed an Internal Web Console for reporting activities and

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering from MANIT BHOPAL, INDIA, 2005-2009 with GPA 7.9/10.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Javascript/NodeJS (LoopbackJS, AngularJS, MEANJS), Core Java (+Jackrabbit, Day CQ), Python (Django), HTML/ HTML5, CSS (Twitter Bootstrap), PHP (Codelgniter, Laravel), Ruby (Rails, Chef), Swift & Objective-C (iOS)
- MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, BDD/TDD (Mocha, Protractor, Selenium), Markdown, AWS Automation (boto, libCloud), Docker, Chef & Capistrano, Video Streaming (HLS/HDS/mpegts)
- Machine Learning, Linux & Shell (Bash Scripting), Continuous Integration & Delivery, Performance Engg. (The Grinder), Photoshop & UX Design

STRENGTHS

- Experience of Product Ownership, Entrepreneurship, Startups and Corporates
- Strong implementation/practical skills in general including electronics, robotics.
- Productivity and Efficiency evangelist.

OPEN SOURCE & PUBLIC CONTRIBUTIONS

- LoopbackJS A rapid development framework for Nodejs with ORM for MongoDB, Redis and SQL databases.
- LinkedIn Passport Token NPM Module: https://www.npmjs.com/package/passport-linkedin-token

ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Organizer & Runner Up of Adobe TT Tournament 2014. Winner of Inter-corporate & college Tournaments
- Two times Winner of Robotics in TechnoSearch 2006 (MANIT Bhopal) and Nexus 2006 by IIT Bombay.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

- Playing TT, Badminton, Tennis, Football, 8 ball Pool & Ice Skating
- Traveling
- Counter Strike & CSGO
- Cooking, Foodie